<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="//purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="//purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="//www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="//search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[startup - Tech Inertia ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Technology & Startup]]></description><link>https://techinertia.com/</link><image><url>https://techinertia.com/favicon.png</url><title>startup - Tech Inertia </title><link>https://techinertia.com/</link></image><generator>Ghost 3.8</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 08:44:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techinertia.com/tag/startup/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[11 Book That Every Startup Enthusiast Should Read]]></title><description><![CDATA[Are you working on a startup idea? Book's i have listed here have shown the path for me and inspired me to keep experimenting for the best solution.]]></description><link>https://techinertia.com/11-books-for-startup-enthusiast/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e50b5a4461cc51db26273eb</guid><category><![CDATA[startup]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nilesh Bhosale]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 05:43:57 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="//res-3.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/Tech%20Inertia/person-holding-brown-ceramic-coffee-mug-824197.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="//res-3.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/Tech%20Inertia/person-holding-brown-ceramic-coffee-mug-824197.jpg" alt="11 Book That Every Startup Enthusiast Should Read"><p>Are you working on a startup idea ? Chances are you are facing challenges in clarity of vision, sharing the vision with team, inspiring more people to join your cause, generating momentum for continuous improvement and many many more. </p><p>Every startup needs a customized approach to suit there needs although certain guidelines can be used to start experimenting what might work. Nevertheless it is a process of constant improvement and balances. </p><p>Book's i have listed here have shown the path for me and inspired me to keep experimenting for the best solution.</p><hr><ul><li>The Phoenix Project: A Novel about IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win - Gene Kim, Kevin Behr and George Spafford</li><li>The Goal: A Process of Ongoing Improvement - Eliyahu M. Goldratt, Jeff Cox</li><li>Can't Hurt Me: Master Your Mind and Defy the Odds - David Goggins</li><li>Measure What Matters: OKRs: The Simple Idea That Drives 10x Growth - John Doerr</li><li>The Infinite Game: How Great Businesses Achieve Long-lasting Success - Simon Sinek</li><li>Outliers: The Story of Success - Malcolm Gladwell</li><li>Antifragile: Things That Gain from Disorder - Nassim Nicholas Taleb</li><li>Start With Why: How Great Leaders Inspire Everyone to Take Action - Simon Sinek</li><li>The Storyteller's Secret: How TED Speakers and Inspirational Leaders Turn Their Passion into Performance - Carmine Gallo</li><li>The Power Of Habit: : Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business - Charles Duhigg</li><li>Groove's Journey To $ 100k In Monthly Revenue - Alex Turnbull </li></ul><hr><p>If you have read books which helped you do let me know by commenting below. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Best Project Management Tools For Beginners]]></title><description><![CDATA[Managing a project can became a difficult task with an evolving product, changing requirement and a new team. You can use this tools to streamline your efforts and provide clarity for everyone on the team.]]></description><link>https://techinertia.com/project-management-tools/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c978ac705150a77f34e534c</guid><category><![CDATA[startup]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nilesh Bhosale]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 03:30:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="//res-2.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/agenda-concept-development-7376_o.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="//res-2.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/agenda-concept-development-7376_o.jpg" alt="The Best Project Management Tools For Beginners"><p>Managing a project can became a difficult task with an evolving product, changing requirement and a new team. You can use this tools to streamline your efforts and provide clarity for everyone on the team.</p><h2 id="why-to-use-this-tools">Why To Use This Tools</h2><p>If you have worked with a small growing team you will realize it gets increasingly complicated to align all team members towards the same target. </p><p>Even if everyone on the team is in the same office it helps to jot down your ideas and make it visible for everyone in team to refer to anytime. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="//res-3.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/quotesCover-jpg-3_o.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="The Best Project Management Tools For Beginners"></figure><h2 id="7-different-tools-you-can-use">7 Different Tools You Can Use</h2><p>I have made a list of tools which i found to be helpful to manage our team tasks. </p><p>Each tool has certain advantages and disadvantages and it comes down to your team preference to selecting which one works best for you.</p><h3 id="trello">Trello</h3><p>The best kanban tool on the market with plethora of tools to help you organize your lists.</p><p>Trello is easy to learn but can get difficult to manage once the number of tasks start to increase. You can use filters and tags to manage this problem in a better way.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tVooja0Ta5I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><h3 id="asana">Asana</h3><p>Choose between lists or kanban for your project and assign dates to view on calendar. </p><p>I personally use and love asana for jotting down all my ideas and track till completion on my calendar.</p><p>This tool has the best UI for calendar view you should definitely check that out. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AW_PDcmjE-o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><h3 id="basecamp">Basecamp</h3><p>Basecamp is a central place your entire team can use to document and store everything related to your projects. </p><p>Basecamp is a paid tool right from start so might not be a good option for a small team.</p><p>Although if you are looking for something which can provide everything your team might need at a central base Basecamp is a must try.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/su5xAZHF114?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><h3 id="monday-com">Monday.com</h3><p>A fairly new tool on the market with a refreshing ui.</p><p>Simple tasks lists can be created and gantt chart view is a delight to eyes. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_31hNiJliFs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><h3 id="jira">Jira</h3><p>Looking for a tried and  tested tool which can handle all your agile sprint documentation concerns? Look no further Jira is the tool for you. </p><p>You can organize your tasks in sprints and track there completion on kanban with process customization. </p><p>Jira can get complicated easily but it comes with the advantage of supreme customer support.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PQa3NFB_LRg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><h3 id="todoist">Todoist</h3><p>If you need something simpler and do not want to complicate things just yet.</p><p>Todoist is a no brainer. Its very easy and intuitive to use.</p><p>The auto text conversion to dates and reminder is a killer feature which i guess no other tool has and makes Todoist a go to tool for many small teams.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ZKq0r-g87M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><h3 id="excel-sheets">Excel Sheets</h3><p>Do not even want to commit to a tool? </p><p>Google sheets can provide for basic tracking for starting teams. Everyone knows how to use this and can be setup quickly with this templates.</p><p>Gantt Chart Template :</p><p><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1JcX4sHAuBRGsbXIgktxj5n72sMyFQutQyqJ7R_xQCCU/edit#gid=0">https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1JcX4sHAuBRGsbXIgktxj5n72sMyFQutQyqJ7R_xQCCU/edit#gid=0</a></p><p>Project Management Template :</p><p><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1gZ_kkrzNMW_u-7FfzX9gWD5V27b-a5eNm7pUPkpfphM/template/preview?usp=drive_web&amp;ouid=%7BuserId%7D">https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1gZ_kkrzNMW_u-7FfzX9gWD5V27b-a5eNm7pUPkpfphM/template/preview?usp=drive_web&amp;ouid=%7BuserId%7D</a></p><h2 id="how-do-you-choose-right-one">How Do You Choose Right One</h2><p>Consider the following points when choosing the right tool for you:</p><ul><li>Prior experience about a tool.</li><li>Does the tool cover all your requirements.</li><li>Costing once your team grows.</li><li>Experiment with few tools to be sure about teams comfort.</li><li>Tool must be aligned with your team dynamics.</li><li>Keep rechecking tool utilization at periodic interval if you are using the tool to optimum or should consider a more suitable one.</li></ul><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="//res-4.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/quotesCover-jpg-4_o.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="The Best Project Management Tools For Beginners"></figure><p>No matter which tool you finalize you should get your team to actually use it. If the team is not motivated to make the most out of the tool, it could just be another clog in the process.</p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>Compare the best project management tools in the market and decide which one you could use in your next project.</p><p>I am using and loving Asana for task planning and management in TechInertia. Although i do love the detailing one can do in Jira and cross team usability of basecamp specially for non technical teams in company.  </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is It Worth Joining A Startup (Even Though Investments Are Fewer Now)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Should you consider finding a job in a startup knowing the fundings have reduced in last few years? ]]></description><link>https://techinertia.com/joining-a-startup/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c83b8bbcc021c1cf271f3d5</guid><category><![CDATA[startup]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nilesh Bhosale]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:42:22 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="//res-4.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/pexels-photo-1204649.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="//res-4.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/pexels-photo-1204649.jpg" alt="Is It Worth Joining A Startup (Even Though Investments Are Fewer Now)"><p></p><p>Should you consider finding a job in a startup knowing the fundings have reduced in last few years? </p><p><strong>Yes</strong> - Definitely. Joining the <strong>right</strong> startup can offer you excellent opportunity to learn and gather all round experience. </p><h2 id="lesser-deals-but-bigger-deal-size">Lesser Deals But Bigger Deal Size</h2><p>The number of investment in startups have reduced although the deal sizes are getting bigger. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://www.theatlas.com/i/atlas_H1bJNZpJN.png" class="kg-image" alt="Is It Worth Joining A Startup (Even Though Investments Are Fewer Now)"></figure><p>“The Indian VC industry is maturing and you are finding proof of funds going after fewer but better quality deals after building their initial portfolio,” Arpan Sheth, partner at Bain &amp; Company and one of the authors of the report, said in the company’s press release.</p><p>This again raises a question how to know if a startup is right for you?</p><h2 id="choosing-right-startup">Choosing Right Startup?</h2><h3 id="has-startup-reached-product-market-fit">Has Startup Reached Product Market Fit?</h3><p>It is important to understand which stage does a startup belong to before deciding to join.</p><ul><li>Idea Stage</li><li>Minimum Viable Product Stage</li><li>Product Market Fit Stage</li><li>Scaling Up Stage</li><li>Establishing</li></ul><p><a href="https://medium.com/@Andy_Areitio">Andy Areitio</a> talks in much depth on this at "<a href="https://medium.com/theventurecity/from-idea-to-scaleup-startup-stages-a268799325d7">From Idea to Scaleup: Startup Stages. Understanding the milestones at every stage toward success</a>"</p><p>Risks of a startup not surviving gets lesser as it grows ahead of each stage. </p><h3 id="what-role-are-you-being-offered">What Role Are You Being Offered?</h3><p>You should be very clear about the role you are going to play in working with any startup. Always clear all your queries with the interviewer or get in touch with HR.</p><p>Startups generally have a variety on openings and if the interviewer could be looking at you from multiple positions. It is always best to clarify this in advance and set the direction right.</p><h3 id="what-could-be-your-growth-track-in-near-future">What Could Be Your Growth Track In Near Future?</h3><p>This question answers how well the startup has planned for you and hence for themselves. Use this to understand more about the work profile. </p><p>Many startups have a ambiguous growth plan and this will certainly be a negative indicator for startup future. </p><h3 id="are-you-a-startup-person">Are You A Startup Person?</h3><p>Finally, the most important question to ask yourself is will you really enjoy working in a startup. Startups offer you ownership over your work but this comes at the cost of dedication and experimentation. If you are not motivated enough to figure out solutions to tough question yourself, it will soon become a hectic workplace.  </p><h2 id="is-it-worth-it">Is It Worth It?</h2><p>Joining a startup can turn out to be a tiring yet a learning process. You can experiment freely with tools available and develop something that solves customer problem. The satisfaction you derive from the direct feedback you receive is tremendous advantage only startups can offer. </p><p>Developing a mindset to solve problems in critical times with very little to no help is the key to it all. </p><p>Rather than waiting for a solution to be derived you must learn to work on it till you find it. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="//res-2.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/My-Post-min.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Is It Worth Joining A Startup (Even Though Investments Are Fewer Now)"></figure><h2 id="my-experience">My Experience</h2><p>I have worked with few startups in domain including education, content delivery network and interior design for product based and a software service based startup in saas model. I have enjoyed working on products that appeal to me. </p><p>Products that you can clearly imagine will help others solve important problems are the once to work on. If you do not connect with higher purpose then may be they are not great fit for you. </p><p>Once you find the right product, starts a self assessing cycle to verify if your efforts are in right direction and helping product growth directly. </p><p>You can help a product in more ways than you can imagine including creating the right culture in team, helping a colleague, brainstorming on a topic startup could benefit from. </p><p>Taking complete ownership in startup starts by understanding your actions would result in startup being successful or failure. This mindset enables you to think out of box for you and your team. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="//res-2.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/My-Post-min-2_o.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Is It Worth Joining A Startup (Even Though Investments Are Fewer Now)"></figure><p>It is important for any startup team to take that extra step towards company culture apart from deliverables to make that zero to one transition for any startup.</p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>Joining a startup can be a overwhelming experience, but if you enjoy ownership and take efforts to solving real life problems you will enjoy the process. </p><p>You should take time and research the startup before joining. Although fundings for new startups have reduced this has filtered the good from bad and presented the right way forward. </p><p>Finally join a company where you would love to put in the extra efforts it will payout for you and company both.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 book's that helped me answer the question "Why should you read?"]]></title><description><![CDATA[Have you wondered on what good reading can do for you? Read this to know how it helped me and why you should start reading too.]]></description><link>https://techinertia.com/why-should-you-read/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0b9c1bcc021c1cf271f0fd</guid><category><![CDATA[startup]]></category><category><![CDATA[software-inspiration]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nilesh Bhosale]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 11:28:16 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="//res-5.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/pexels-photo-256541.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="//res-5.cloudinary.com/techinertia-com/image/upload/q_auto/v1/techinertia/2019/04/pexels-photo-256541.jpg" alt="10 book's that helped me answer the question "Why should you read?""><p></p><p>It all started a few years back when i decided to read few book's one of my colleague spoke highly of (Zero to One). We were working in a small startup based in powai (<a href="https://mumbaimirror.indiatimes.com/mumbai/other/has-mumbai-finally-got-its-silicon-valley/articleshow/45891283.cms">silicon valley of mumbai</a>) trying to figure out how to get customer's and what best use our skill's to get exponential growth. He was right, it's a insightful book with view's of Peter Thiel on what it really meant to start something new with real life example's. During this time one of my relative asked me the question "Why should you read in first place?". Wouldn't it effect our original thought process and divert efforts in things that worked for other people in different setting. Its a valid point which got me to think whether that would really be the case. </p><p>I enjoyed reading Zero to One and followed my intuition to read more books. To figure out whether reading really helps or not, i had to read a few many first. What i realized during this process was i liked reading books which i found inspiring or have mentions of the problem which i am struggling with or share failure experiences of others who have tried before. So reading books sure had a positive impact on the way i thought about things. It inspired me to go one step further, showed how others have found way when it looked like the end of road and learning from experience of others can help broaden the scope of my views. </p><p>Summing up the answer to "<strong>Why should you read?</strong>"</p><ul><li>Inspires you to keep on doing the things you love. </li><li>Broadens your scope of looking at a problem.</li><li>Presents guidelines for solving a problem, on which we can start and develop a process that works for us.</li><li>Teaches us about the topics we have not dealt with.</li><li>Sharing this knowledge with colleagues and relatives helps them too.</li></ul><p>Although i would agree its not that reading books is the only way to learn and grow. It helps if you really like doing it. Finally what really matters is getting it done. One thing i have definitely learnt from reading is it wont happen on its own, you have to keep the book down and get to work. </p><p>Doing is by the best way to learn and nothing can substitute that. Although it certainly helps to take out some time and learn something new from others. May be it inspires a solution to problem you are already facing or might face. </p><p>Finally, the must read list of books : -</p><ol><li>Zero to One - Peter Thiel</li><li>Power Of Habit - Charles Duhigg</li><li>Deliverying Happyness - Tony Hsieh</li><li>The Alchemist - Paulo Coelho</li><li>Scaling Up Excellence - Hayagreeva Rao and Robert I. Sutton</li><li>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck - Mark Manson</li><li>The Art of the Start 2.0 - <a href="https://www.amazon.in/s/ref=dp_byline_sr_ebooks_1?ie=UTF8&amp;text=Guy+Kawasaki&amp;search-alias=digital-text&amp;field-author=Guy+Kawasaki&amp;sort=relevancerank">Guy Kawasaki</a> </li><li>Rich Dad Poor Dad - Robert Kiyosaki and Sharon Lechter</li><li>Growth Hacker Marketing - <a href="https://www.amazon.in/Ryan-Holiday/e/B007LUHFH8/ref=dp_byline_cont_book_1">Ryan Holiday</a></li><li>The Lean StartupBook - Eric Ries</li></ol><p>Please leave your comments with your thoughts on "Why should you read?".  I would love to know what you think on it. </p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>